

Dallas, TX 75077 | (C) 972-330-9915 | jeremy.cai@ymail.com

https://capapple.github.io/MyPage/

Professional Summary

Experienced full stack developer with a passion for logics and design, proficient with the latest technologies and tools for building a user-focused web presence from the ground up.

Passionate about learning and researching and enjoys approaching programming challenges from different angles and collaborating with team.

Dedicated, highly organized and self-disciplined, attended and stood out in a very intense full-stack-developer training program while working a full time job.

Skills

- HTML/CSS
- jQuery
- Express
- MySQL React

- Bootstrap
- Firebase
- MVC
- MongoDB
- ES6

- JavaScript
- Node.js
- RESTful API
- JAVA
- GIT

Work History

Full Stack Developer Student

Southern Methodist University

09/2018 to Current

- Mastered modern developing techniques by spending 30 hours a week learning and practicing. Developed, tested and debugged web applications including but not limiting to the ones below.
- Built a restaurant app that logs users' order with Node.js, using MVC design pattern. Used jQuery and AJAX on the client side. Wrote ORM file and used Express.js on the server side to set up routes and parse data. Established connection with MySQL using mysql npm package.
- Collaborated with a team and developed an entertainment app that provides information on local events, restaurants and trends based on geo location. Used AJAX to get JSON from Seat Geek and Google API. Efficiently practiced version control by using Git and Github.
- Developed a train schedule app that can display, take in and store data by using jQuery, Moment.js and NoSQL cloud database (Firebase).
- Developed personal website using HTML/CSS, implemented grids and responsive design by using Bootstrap.

Producer/Web Editor 03/2015 to 03/2018

2LanesStudio – Dallas, TX

- Created, styled and managed static websites for local small businesses with HTML and CSS.
- Increased client's brand awareness by defining and recommending detailed solutions to capturing images.

Education

Full Stack Developer Certificate

2018 to current

Southern Methodist University - Dallas, TX

Master of Science: Accounting

08/2012 to 12/2014

University of Texas at Dallas - Dallas, TX

Bachelor of Engineering: Automation **Jiaotong University** - Shaanxi, China

08/2008to 06/2012